# Hartej Lehal

### Web Developer

I am Tej, a web developer with a Bachelor degree in Computer Science. I love creating accessible, responsive and well designed applications that will create an impact in your business. I bring strong problem-solving skills and 2 years of experience as a Software Developer with Javascript, React, HTML, CSS. I'm always eager to learn new skills that will improve my development skill.

tejlehal13@gmail.com

e tejlehal.com

y twitter.com/TejLehal

+16475153320

in linkedin.com/in/hartejlehal

github.com/hplehal

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

### **Programming Languages:**

Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, Java, Python,

### Frameworks & Libraries

React, Redux, JQuery, SASS

#### **Databases**

Firebase, APIs, SQL, MongoDB

### Design

Photoshop, Illustrator

#### Tools

Version Control(Git/Github), Figma, Kanban(Trello), Netlify,

### **SKILLS**

WACAG 2 Accessibility Standard

Responsive Design

**Problem Solving** 

Teamwork

Organization

**Growth Minded** 

### **EDUCATION**

### **B.Sc Computer Science**

Ryerson University

09/2013 - 04/2017

Toronto, ON

### Immersive Web Development Bootcamp

Juno College of Technology

05/2020 - 07/2020

Toronto, ON

### **HACKATHONS**

## Hack Toronto Police (Toronto Police Service) (06/2018)

Created an application that helps deal with the issues in the community and lessen the 911 calls for the police which is a main issue that the Toronto Police are having.

### Capital One (Gift the Code)

Created a data retrieving application using Google Cloud Platform and Vision API that will retrieve informations for Careers Education Empowerment a non profit organization that helps young black professionals succeed.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **Software Developer** Findspace

07/2018 - 08/2019

Toronto, ON

Commercial Real Estate Leasing and Marketing Platform that manage, market & lease commercial real estate portfolio

- Released a new version of Findspace Application using React which will help with better organization of building properties and leases.
- Created and worked on a plugin that improved the visual presentation of building plans.
- Used and managed Findspace's web infrastructures. React, Redux, Python, Amazon EC2, S3.

## Front End Developer Web on Demand

01/2018 - 08/2018

Vaughn, ON

Building custom websites for small businesses to enterprises.

- Building Websites using HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Used effective SEO techniques to help promote the websites.
- Created New Templates for the company's CMS.

### Assistant Manager Cecilia Trucking Ltd.

08/2019 – 05/2020 Mississauga, ON Family Owned Trucking Company that haul in Ontario, Quebec and parts of the USA

- Organized the trips for the drivers.
- Made sure that all the trucks are ready to be used.
- Created an excel sheet that are used to keep track of time sheet of each truck drivers.

### PERSONAL PROJECTS

DROPiN | React, Firebase, APIs, CSS3, HTML5 🗷

 Used Google Places API, Browser Geolocation API and Mapbox API to store show where the pickup game is located.

Sorting Visualizer | JQuery, SASS, HTML5, CSS3 🗷

 Created a Visual representation of the 3 popular sorting algorithms (mergesort, quicksort, bubblesort)

Question Impossible | JQuery, SASS, HTML5, CSS3, APIs ♂

 A triva game that will randomly give user's categories to answer and will see the results after all the questions were answered